Kostadis Roussos: Hello, folks.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm here.
Kostadis Roussos: Folks, can you hear me?
Wade: I can hear you.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, good.
Kostadis Roussos: Because you're all… you're all darkened…
Wade: I was like, bro.
Kostadis Roussos: Gary, say one sec.
Wade: Let me… Turn on the lights…
Kostadis Roussos: It's been time to create the Titanic battle.
David Mendenhall: Really? Titanic? Really?
Kostadis Roussos: this?
David Mendenhall: Where's the drama?
David Mendenhall: Here's the media?
Kostadis Roussos: I'll give you drama. Give me a second, I got prepared.
Wade: there's drama?
Kostadis Roussos: trauma.
Wade: I like other people's drama.
David Mendenhall: You're the drama.
Wade: I'm trauma?
David Mendenhall: In this… in this quest, you are the drama.
Wade: Oh, well, yes, okay.
Wade: In general, I'm not.
Wade: What, buddy? Get out of here.
David Mendenhall: Can you have advantage and disadvantage on initiative?
Wade: Advantage on initiative? What would that even mean? Roll twice.
David Mendenhall: And get a plus 5.
Wade: I mean… It's just a bonus, not advantage, right?
David Mendenhall: Yeah, interesting.
Kostadis Roussos: What are you talking about?
Kostadis Roussos: I don't know whether I approve of this.
David Mendenhall: Well, according to D&D Beyond.
David Mendenhall: If you… maybe if you use a heroic inspiration on your initiative, you get a plus 5?
Wade: Oh, well, that makes sense.
Kostadis Roussos: That does, actually.
Wade: Seems pretty tame.
David Mendenhall: What is God.
Wade: What's going on behind you, Gary?
Gary Young: She has a dog that is a squishable thing, so she was, stepping on it.
Wade: Cute puppy.
Gary Young: that.
Wade: How's it get along with the cats?
Gary Young: I thought you were in Batsuria.
Gary Young: Okay, goodbye.
Kostadis Roussos: Wow, that was very passive-aggressive there, Gary.
Wade: Here I was, trying to…
Gary Young: Includer.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, well done. Very well done.
David Mendenhall: I haven't seen Arlo in a long time.
Kostadis Roussos: F.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Wade: Did anybody read the summary?
Kostadis Roussos: Does anybody remember?
David Mendenhall: There was no…
Gary Young: Something, something.
David Mendenhall: There was no summary.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
Wade: somewhere?
Kostadis Roussos: There it was.
Gary Young: There was a summary.
Kostadis Roussos: There was even a summary of the summary.
David Mendenhall: I got a preview. Oh, there's a thread.
Wade: Yeah… dude, Google Chat is useless, it always has been. It didn't spread, that's why I didn't find it. Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Sorry.
Wade: Google Chat.
David Mendenhall: Oh, no, I did. I read this. Yeah, I read this.
Kostadis Roussos: I had some fun with the credentials.
David Mendenhall: I'm selling out, yes.
David Mendenhall: I think maybe I am selling out, we'll see how that goes.
Kostadis Roussos: Like, I thought of… I thought, you know, it'll be… you were… it wasn't the… it wasn't the dialogue, just for the record.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, no, no, no, no, he didn't make anything up.
Kostadis Roussos: Ugh.
David Mendenhall: I approve the summary.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
David Mendenhall: Whenever you're ready.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, yes, okay, so… I just suddenly was rereading the thing I wrote and was like, but it was kind of fun. All right, okay. Okay.
Wade: Let's see if we get… oh man, I'm logged out.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, oh, oh, there's, like, there's some… oh, Gary, I can now answer the question of the dueling character sheets.
Gary Young: Two-linked character sheets. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So the guy who works on DN… on… Beyond…
Kostadis Roussos: 20, right, who gets paid more money, and does this as a free service, has a bug in his code, which he refuses to fix.
Kostadis Roussos: And…
Gary Young: She refuses to fix.
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, he has… I'm being an asshole person complaining about somebody who does something for free that doesn't get paid, right?
Gary Young: priorities, and this is an unpaid priority.
Kostadis Roussos: Got it. And so, it doesn't work if you have more… it only… there's a bug that if you have two.
Wade: things open?
Kostadis Roussos: It only rec- it only recognizes one.
Wade: But only character sheets, right? Because I'm always pulling open monster sheets, and it's fine.
Kostadis Roussos: For character sheets, it only recognizes one.
Gary Young: But, but it used to work.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, there's a bug in his code.
Gary Young: There's a bug in the new code.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, well, or there's a change.
David Mendenhall: to the ground.
Kostadis Roussos: There was a regression, and you know, his test harness was inadequate, and frankly, I don't know why he isn't prioritizing this over whatever else he thinks might be important.
Gary Young: Well, you got a bug, the first thing you do is roll back. You don't try to, like, push forward.
Kostadis Roussos: I think… I think the problem is not that he has a bug, but that
Kostadis Roussos: role D&D Beyond changed this interface, and he hasn't figured out how to debug this code yet.
Wade: Rolling back in production is a serious hassle, too, because usually there's a database migration that you then have to unwind, and sometimes can't.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah. So, regardless…
Gary Young: Does D&D… does Beyond 20 require database migration?
Wade: It might, I mean, it's got a whole bunch of… whenever you add new features.
Gary Young: I see what you're saying. Yeah, okay.
Wade: Super side, right? Like, all your… all your stuff is in the cloud, like, I don't have anything local.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so I don't know. So regardless, regardless of the situation, I just thought everybody should know.
Kostadis Roussos: That there is a bug, I have identified the bug, and I'm very disappointed with this free volunteer's inability to focus on what matters.
Wade: You could volunteer.
Gary Young: We're buying a coffee.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, I've already bought him coffee before.
Gary Young: Well, I mean, like…
Wade: I bought him a cup of coffee, so he owes me.
Gary Young: Copy in, get code out. I mean, that's the…
Kostadis Roussos: No, I was just kind of encouraging him to keep the product updated, that was why I did it.
Gary Young: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: I don't know, so yeah, so there's some bug.
Gary Young: I mean, I'm working… Yeah, like, if I really wanted to, I guess I could, like, open up two different windows that are in different browsers.
Wade: Two browsers, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Or, you know, you could, you know, go read the code and fix the bug.
Gary Young: Oh, well… We do that too, but…
Kostadis Roussos: Is it actually… is there a repo that we could actually, you know, fix it ourselves? Yeah, there's… well, Mr. Retiree here might have some free time. Alright.
Gary Young: I have 10 more days until I'm free again.
Gary Young: I am,
Gary Young: I am unfortunately going to India for 2 weeks, in a week and a half, so…
Kostadis Roussos: Well, that didn't stop you from playing last time.
Gary Young: Yes, I will… I will certainly endeavor to make an attempt, so…
Wade: Tim you into it.
Kostadis Roussos: Little shame it didn't stop you last time.
Gary Young: It should work, but just kind of, like, warning about the chaos embedding.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, no worries, alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so, the party enters, let's see, let me just, get everything set up, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so let me just see if I can… alright. You step into a clearing, relatively approximately 60 feet across, but something feels wrong. The dense woods surround you. Stop, lean forward unnaturally, your twisted bark gleaming like obsidian and the faint, eerie light filtering through the broken canopy above.
Kostadis Roussos: Pools of iridescent sap shimmer at scattered points, their colors shifting hypnotically. The thick underbrush your feet is blackened and thorny, snagging at your armored skin. At the heart of the clearing stands an immense tree and…
Kostadis Roussos: Like figure, its limbs bending in impossible geometries, dripping glowing sap into a pool nearby.
Kostadis Roussos: Near it, faint flickering tears in reality. Near it, faint flickering tears in reality, pulse softly, whispering promises of power and madness.
Kostadis Roussos: So, you also notice,
David Mendenhall: It does not sound like fair trade power.
Gary Young: I hope the promise of madness is not like a, you know, like a bait and switch, because we need that madness.
Wade: I… I disagree. I didn't need the madness.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay… Alrighty.
David Mendenhall: But we agree, Gary. Neither of us wants the power.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, fair enough.
Kostadis Roussos: Fair enough, fair enough. Alright, you also notice, members, what are obviously members of the Emerald Enclave.
Wade: It's the first party.
David Mendenhall: My fans!
Kostadis Roussos: One of them shouts, they are…
David Mendenhall: be soon.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, of course. Let's see. The.
Gary Young: They're currently…
Kostadis Roussos: trapped in the… they're currently trapped. It's almost as if the.
David Mendenhall: Treant has controlled the Brambley Woods to… Oh, Treiant.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, okay, so yes, need to put some… I need to put some, monsters.
David Mendenhall: 138 hit points, woo!
David Mendenhall: Woo!
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, it's not that.
David Mendenhall: AC!
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, that's… it's a little bit different.
David Mendenhall: Oh.
David Mendenhall: You're… you're not following the Monster Manual.
Kostadis Roussos: No.
David Mendenhall: prerogative.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, wow.
Wade: Creativity allowed.
Kostadis Roussos: We play 4th edition, where you're not allowed to make decisions.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, 16 endpoints.
Kostadis Roussos: The transit's 110.
David Mendenhall: Oh, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, alright, but you're supposed to have, you know, you're, you know… alright.
Kostadis Roussos: So, Lyra… so the woman here shouts.
Kostadis Roussos: sees you, notices that, Soma is a druid.
Wade: Soma's a bear.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, someone's a bear?
Wade: I never took… took the form off.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, okay. Counting on you to keep track of the.
David Mendenhall: Oh, I have an idea.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you want to hear what she says, or do you want to, like, you know.
David Mendenhall: Sure, no, no, no, no.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, yes.
David Mendenhall: I just have an idea.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, help us. So, she goes, My name is Lyra. Help us! We're out of the Emerald Enclave! This thing! It was the Grove's Guardian, but it has been corrupted. We are trying to serve her of planar infection when it turned on us. Please, you have to fight it! Don't let the corruption spread!
David Mendenhall: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so, Soma, can you understand common when you're a bear?
Wade: My understanding is that, yes, the… you… you… Can, yeah.
Wade: Let me just check.
Gary Young: I mean, sometimes you have to communicate as a bear before you do your deed.
David Mendenhall: Definitely.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, let me go to characters and… And… we're very… Well, if you may…
Kostadis Roussos: You're a bear, right? Is that what I heard?
Wade: I'm a bear.
Kostadis Roussos: Find some of the bear.
Kostadis Roussos: So I'm there.
Gary Young: Yeah, you can understand, but you can't speak.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, that's what I thought.
Wade: Yeah, so I'm kind of mute. I can roar.
Kostadis Roussos: Rounds.
David Mendenhall: But if somebody else casts Speak with Animals, then they… can understand you. Yeah.
Wade: I can also just drop, I have got… I got shapes out the wazoo because of the subclass.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
David Mendenhall: Alright, well, I'm ready to cast a spell when I'm allowed to do that.
Wade: Oh, I guess I should roll initiative.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so people should roll.
Wade: Alright, and what's that? An 11? There we go.
David Mendenhall: 15.
Wade: Looks like you'll be first, then.
David Mendenhall: Mr. Spellcaster.
Kostadis Roussos: Oops.
Wade: I…
Kostadis Roussos: You can't move.
Wade: I've got my last… Midpoints were…
David Mendenhall: So it's my understanding that the… the tree is holding the… the party? Is that it? The… the druids from the Emerald Enclave? It's holding them?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, the elves are currently restrained by thick, thorny vines. You cannot…
Kostadis Roussos: So, can… okay, so let me see…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, let's go… let me go to the initiative die rule.
Kostadis Roussos: Just so the record.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, maybe you can explain to me what's going on here. So there's 1, 2, and 3…
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on, give me a second to just make sure I… okay.
Kostadis Roussos: What's this initiative?
Kostadis Roussos: Nope.
Kostadis Roussos: There's a roll-off between me and Brewbarry.
Kostadis Roussos: We're married?
Kostadis Roussos: Brewbarry.
Gary Young: Natural one.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, well, it might be the case that,
Kostadis Roussos: I rolled a 6, so that means you rolled a 5.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, let's actually do it, 10.5.
Kostadis Roussos: No.
Kostadis Roussos: Big 10 point flat.
David Mendenhall: Treant gets 10.5.
Kostadis Roussos: No, and…
David Mendenhall: 10.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, sorry, 10.5, and this guy gets 10.0.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Gary Young: Yeah, that looks right.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, let me just sort again.
Kostadis Roussos: There we go. Alright. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: The various, ensnared folks can't do anything until you remove them from their ensnarement, just so you know. Alright, so, you were asking questions.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Dave. So, here's what's going on. You have these magical wells,
Kostadis Roussos: I haven't put the word well in all of them, but let me just, so that there's no confusion later, I will just…
Kostadis Roussos: There's another well over here.
Wade: Well, well, well…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, these are magical wells.
David Mendenhall: Should we put the thorns on the initiative tracker?
Kostadis Roussos: Thorns, thorns can only attack you when you enter within 10 feet of them.
David Mendenhall: Understood. But the thorns are what are holding the elves.
Kostadis Roussos: Ugh.
David Mendenhall: So to free the elves, we would have to destroy the thorns.
David Mendenhall: Okay, so they should be on the tracker, because.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
David Mendenhall: bring the… elves so they can participate in fighting the Treant seems prudent.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, no, no, I'm just trying to think, do they need to be…
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, alright. Let me just get the, I get her initiative.
David Mendenhall: They could probably also… Gas spells?
Kostadis Roussos: We can'.
David Mendenhall: They cannot cast well ensnared.
Kostadis Roussos: You're… they're being held.
David Mendenhall: They're out of spell points.
Kostadis Roussos: No, they're gone out of spell points, they can't move.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh.
David Mendenhall: I can't do somatic components.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: So they're kind of… they're kind of caught in it. That's why they're kind of feeling a little bit out of.
David Mendenhall: Correct.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on.
Kostadis Roussos: Bucks tied underneath.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, let's not give them… they will… they will not have… let me see if my… unfortunately, I think I did something to do Google Docs that caused it to crash.
Kostadis Roussos: Which is very nice.
Kostadis Roussos: So, for this encounter, the brambles will not attack. They will just be grappling the creatures. They are currently focused on that.
David Mendenhall: K.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
David Mendenhall: I don't see myself on the board.
Kostadis Roussos: That's because I put two Valphine and not one Vukradin.
Kostadis Roussos: Because I am dyslexic, and I get confused.
David Mendenhall: Maybe don't have to verify the… berry should be not near… Brambles.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: So…
David Mendenhall: Alright, the elves, are they all equal, or is there one that's, like, the leader?
Wade: Who's the head?
Kostadis Roussos: Mass.
Wade: Find the head druid.
Kostadis Roussos: Is it you can ask.
Kostadis Roussos: Who's in charge here?
David Mendenhall: Yep, who's in charge here?
Kostadis Roussos: She goes, who are you?
David Mendenhall: I'm helping Soma the bear.
Gary Young: Is it that fancy icon in the top right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so she goes, I am Lyra. I am the… I am the lead of this group.
David Mendenhall: Okay? And she is ensnared by… so this thing that's ensnared… this is one…
Kostadis Roussos: Ramble, that's trapped 2 creatures? 3.
David Mendenhall: Correct?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah, it's correct, too, sorry.
David Mendenhall: Even better.
Wade: Yeah, that seems to be the primary target, then.
David Mendenhall: Alright.
Wade: I mean, raw.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, go for it.
David Mendenhall: Command drop.
David Mendenhall: Wisdom save.
Kostadis Roussos: You had to, like, do something like that? So now, like, I have to go figure out what the stat block is? Thank you, that…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Wade: Oh wait, can you only command things that are sentient? Like, anyway…
David Mendenhall: It does any creature, and it must…
Wade: Oh yeah, we discussed this. Ramples are creatures.
David Mendenhall: We used, we, we actually used this last week.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, no, I'm not… Anything that it is holding.
Kostadis Roussos: I get it, I get it, I'm not disputing it.
David Mendenhall: I'm just…
Wade: Excellent.
David Mendenhall: Getting it a little…
Kostadis Roussos: No, I'm trying to find…
David Mendenhall: Oh, you'll probably make the save, and it'll be moved.
Kostadis Roussos: Here we go. Blighted Vine, here we go. Blighted vine, alright. So, put their, alright.
Kostadis Roussos: 5. I found it.
Wade: Pardon.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Wade: It's been a day.
Kostadis Roussos: I will just… all the Blighted Vines attack at the same time. They're declaring it to be one monster.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, 14. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Sorts, too.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so you, you do blight, you tell it to blighted, you tell it to release the creatures. Alright, what do I… what do I… what's my saving throw?
Kostadis Roussos: I think I figured this out a second ago, and it's a Wisdom saving throw, and it's got a plus zero.
Wade: That's higher than I'd expect.
Kostadis Roussos: But .
David Mendenhall: Better than 50.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, wait, hold on, hold on. Does command require… oh, damn…
Kostadis Roussos: Does it need to be able… do you need to be able to communicate in its language? It's, like, the interesting question.
Kostadis Roussos: I made the saving throw.
David Mendenhall: as predicted.
Kostadis Roussos: It's worth it.
Wade: You knew it wasn't gonna work, why did you do it?
Kostadis Roussos: Because this is Vukradin, and he has this ego thing, where instead of actually damaging things, he wants to give command performances and declare to people what needs to happen. Is that it?
Wade: I was really hoping he'd just viciously mock them, but, you know…
David Mendenhall: They probably would have made that save, too.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
David Mendenhall: Roll 17, you can make lots of saves.
Kostadis Roussos: The creature, the blighted vines hold on to everyone. The treant, as you stare at the treant, I mean, or you look at the triant, or you notice the triant.
Kostadis Roussos: In… in a way that guarantees you will not be accidentally
Kostadis Roussos: Inflicted by any diseases or whatnot.
Kostadis Roussos: What you notice is it's a towering trend whose bark is glossy, obedient.
Kostadis Roussos: Obsidian, weeping iridescent sap. Its limbs bend into impossible angles.
Kostadis Roussos: And its voice echoes with overlapping whispers.
Kostadis Roussos: Its movements are less like a living plant and more like a glitch in reality.
Kostadis Roussos: So… It looks like it's been somehow twisted.
Kostadis Roussos: By some kind of planar energies.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. The… Since nobody's within 10 feet.
Kostadis Roussos: the… the vines just hold onto them. Apparently, the treant is amused to watch… Lyra and her…
Kostadis Roussos: compatriots trapped.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Who's next?
Wade: I think that's me.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Wade: So, I think I entered the range.
Kostadis Roussos: Does anybody tell her… tell them that you guys are,
Kostadis Roussos: That she's a druid, or are you guys gonna just pretend that she's, you know, your friendly neighborhood pet bear?
David Mendenhall: I think druids are smart like that.
Wade: Let her figure it out on her own.
David Mendenhall: Fine. She's not going anywhere.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, okay.
Wade: I enter the binds, do they attack when I get in range, or is that a…
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah, they do. They do.
Wade: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: We're in.
Kostadis Roussos: Right. Yes, they attack DC… ACG, plus 4.
Kostadis Roussos: They hit for 4 points of damage.
Wade: Oh, dear.
Kostadis Roussos: I don't know if that's a deer.
Wade: Oh, bear.
Kostadis Roussos: But… Yes.
Wade: Alright, then yeah, we're gonna take a couple of swings at those guys… First hit…
Wade: Let's make this public, and that looks like a… let's see, on the Blighted Vine, they're a 12, so that's a miss.
Kostadis Roussos: Hmm.
Wade: Second attack.
Wade: I hit myself.
David Mendenhall: Gonna be one of those days.
Kostadis Roussos: the trend lies.
Wade: We're not used to being a bear, right?
Kostadis Roussos: I'm sorry, there was just so… there were just so many things that went through my twisted and sick head at that point.
David Mendenhall: You take damage, bear?
Wade: I took some, yeah, I meant 25 out of 20.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
David Mendenhall: Oh, I just… See it on the tracker.
Wade: Oh, sorry, yeah…
Wade: It's annoying, because I get a lot of bonus HP every time I do this.
Wade: Oh, actually, I should… should have been at, 27 plus 9 is 36, minus 4 is 32.
Kostadis Roussos: One of the other members of the group shouts, You there! I don't know who you are, but you look capable. We can reward you. We have resources, information about the forces at play in this region. Just get us out of these vines and help us put that core creature out of its misery.
David Mendenhall: Did they not realize that we're helping them?
Gary Young: You kind of cast a spell that hasn't had done anything, there's a bear…
Gary Young: I'm just saying, this guy over here, he hasn't quite figured out that the bear is, you know.
David Mendenhall: Okay.
David Mendenhall: I will try to avoid being offended.
David Mendenhall: I'm trying hard.
David Mendenhall: I'm digging deep on this one.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, fine, let me rewrite what he wrote. All right, fine. Okay. What did you… what did you do, Gary?
Gary Young: Sorry, I'm just, I'm making, Roll20 icons for my thing, so I don't have to, like.
Gary Young: It's crumble.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
David Mendenhall: The triumph is up.
Kostadis Roussos: Now the trend is up. The trion goes… Alright, what does he do?
Wade: Trees don't talk?
Wade: What's that?
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so the triumph sort of… The aunt looks at you.
Kostadis Roussos: And, besides…
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, stay out of my grove. If you stay out of my grove and let me be, then I will not attack you. And so, since you haven't quite entered the grove, he hasn't yet attacked you.
David Mendenhall: Oh, that's good.
David Mendenhall: Brewbarry.
Gary Young: Alright.
David Mendenhall: Not now.
Gary Young: So I will, I will grow.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
David Mendenhall: Oh, boy.
Gary Young: And so I have 15 feet reach.
David Mendenhall: Nice.
Wade: He big boys!
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
David Mendenhall: What are you gonna attack first?
Gary Young: This, Vine over here.
Gary Young: which I can attack from… Well, out of its reach.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Gary Young: And then, did that do anything?
Gary Young: We're very smash bad guy.
Gary Young: With a 9 attack roll, does it hit?
Kostadis Roussos: No, that's a miss.
Wade: Nope, none of us can hit it.
David Mendenhall: Alright, Valphine, you wanna take a stab at it?
Kostadis Roussos: Lyra, Lyra goes, Miyoki has abandoned us!
David Mendenhall: Well…
Gary Young: Right.
David Mendenhall: We've got lots of rounds.
Kostadis Roussos: Lyra looks… hold on. Alright, Lyra looks at… The drown and says.
David Mendenhall: Hey!
David Mendenhall: This is.
Gary Young: Smocking is my thing.
Kostadis Roussos: Don't know, don't know, she says, she says.
Gary Young: A cleric of a drow that is a cleric of Lathander? Can this be?
Gary Young: Why, yes.
David Mendenhall: Let's see.
Gary Young: Gloriously painful in the lights.
Gary Young: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Gary Young: wait a second, hold on.
Gary Young: Alright, so I need to figure out something to do with my action, and then I will… do a thing, and then…
Gary Young: Oh, did that do something?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, I rolled a DC-13. It's like Dexterity save.
Gary Young: Oh, fine. No, no, no.
Gary Young: Interesting. So, like, some things are coming through with the Beyond 20, but not everything.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Gary Young: Okay. Well, anyway, we can do, will that do something?
David Mendenhall: 19 bolt?
Kostadis Roussos: Yep, that hits… that's a 14 guiding bolt.
Gary Young: Okay. Did it roll damage?
David Mendenhall: 14 pounds?
Kostadis Roussos: Yep, 14 damage.
Gary Young: on… the vines?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so they will go down to 12.
Wade: And then next person to attack them has advantage.
Gary Young: Yep. Should help.
Gary Young: I guess that's me.
David Mendenhall: Give it a shot.
Gary Young: Your cotton.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, I think I'm thinking about the best… Way to go here.
Wade: Command drop again!
Kostadis Roussos: Starry Whip.
David Mendenhall: That's a hit.
Wade: Where's…
Kostadis Roussos: What is it? Yes, risk. That is a hit.
David Mendenhall: Even without it… well, I guess I have advantage, so I should probably roll it twice.
Wade: Okay, my crap.
David Mendenhall: Just in case I get a crit.
David Mendenhall: I do not.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
David Mendenhall: Nice.
Kostadis Roussos: Who's that?
David Mendenhall: Jesus fucking Christ.
Kostadis Roussos: One of those nights.
Kostadis Roussos: This is going to be a long combat, I think.
David Mendenhall: Can't.
Wade: Hope you had another.
David Mendenhall: What are their plans tonight? Alright, Blighted Vine, do you want to mock me?
Gary Young: You should.
David Mendenhall: I deserve it.
Kostadis Roussos: No. No, instead the blighted Vine.
Kostadis Roussos: What will the blooded vine do?
Kostadis Roussos: You're 10 feet away, Soma's here.
David Mendenhall: Everyone's far away.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, it's currently holding on to everybody. It… it does… it… oh, what it does is it releases… no, it can't keep… the… it… you sense it wants to do something, but it's kind of holding on to… to the two creatures… to the two characters, and so strikes at Soma.
Wade: No, not so much.
Kostadis Roussos: And it's, I think…
Wade: 16 is, yeah, that's what you need to hit.
Kostadis Roussos: 4 points of damage.
Wade: Oh, wait.
Wade: Oh, no, I think I inherit the Bears AC at 16.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I'd be 17 in turtle form. Alright.
Wade: How much damage?
Kostadis Roussos: 4 points of damage.
Wade: Take me down to 28. You almost got me to my base HP!
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
David Mendenhall: Europe, so I'm.
Wade: Yeah, well, and I attack back. Let's go. Let's try to…
David Mendenhall: Your 11 points of damage, that'd be awesome.
Wade: I mean… Been known to do it before, just… hey, there's a hit.
David Mendenhall: Alright, with 12 damage. Hooray!
Kostadis Roussos: You, yes, you, you damage the vines. Yay! The vines!
David Mendenhall: design.
Wade: I assume just this cluster.
David Mendenhall: So, so they're free, right? Are they excited?
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on.
Wade: Well, those two are.
David Mendenhall: We'll get the other ones eventually.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, hold on, let me just… okay, so let me get… I need to go figure this out. Okay, so you got her out.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
David Mendenhall: Her and ELF1.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, her an elf one.
Kostadis Roussos: So…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: So, she explains… what does she explain? She says, we were in the midst of performing a ritual, to perform… to perform a ritual.
Kostadis Roussos: And, as a result of freeing her, She waves her little hand.
Kostadis Roussos: And 4 stones appear.
David Mendenhall: Do you like avant-garde music?
Kostadis Roussos: She looks at you as if you are insane.
Wade: Oh, what just appeared?
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so she points…
David Mendenhall: She doesn't like music? Everybody likes music.
Kostadis Roussos: Married.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so what she says is…
Kostadis Roussos: We need to complete the ritual.
David Mendenhall: Okay…
Kostadis Roussos: on, on…
Wade: that we do.
Kostadis Roussos: On the stones to clear… to seal the rift.
David Mendenhall: Okay, how do we do that? What do we need to do?
Kostadis Roussos: Here.
Kostadis Roussos: She goes… she does point out that… okay, so here's it is.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, performing… okay, so, pretty simple rules.
Kostadis Roussos: Here, I'll just drop them… the Google Chat, because that is the only…
David Mendenhall: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: No, because…
Wade: chat.
David Mendenhall: Amazing.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, I'm using Google Chat.
Wade: It's fine.
Kostadis Roussos: Here you go.
David Mendenhall: Whoa.
David Mendenhall: fix ritual actions before accumulating 3 failures?
Kostadis Roussos: That's…
Wade: Well, I at least get advantage on the wisdom ones.
Wade: We probably have some good, clerical on the religion, right?
David Mendenhall: I can do De- I can do sleight of hand.
Wade: Jesus, DC15 on the Wisdom? Even with Advantage, it's gonna suck.
Kostadis Roussos: You can use, help.
Kostadis Roussos: So you can roll with the Vantage.
Wade: I… I roll with Advantage naturally, on that one.
Wade: Well, I mean, with helpless…
David Mendenhall: Failures and were out, wow, and I already burned all my bardic inspirations, so that's not good.
Kostadis Roussos: Whoa.
David Mendenhall: Not good.
Wade: Alright.
Wade: Soma still has another attack,
Wade: So I guess we go try to free Elf, too? Is he among these brambles?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Wade: Alright, then, yeah… I'll still stay out of the Treance Grove, I'm taking the long way around.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me just do this.
Wade: Sure.
Kostadis Roussos: We're just going to do this so that I can remember to keep these guys. These guys are gone.
Kostadis Roussos: Thank you.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, is that.
Wade: Is this… yeah, is this sufficient to free ELF2 over here if I want these?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Wade: Alright, so that's, let's see, I did a bite, so I have a claw yet.
Kostadis Roussos: Literally.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me just add…
David Mendenhall: This one's at, what, 26?
Wade: Well, it's now 17 lower.
David Mendenhall: Okay. Or, no, I guess it's 11 lower.
David Mendenhall: 11 lower.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, 15.
Wade: It's not a very good crit. Oh well.
Kostadis Roussos: Hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Wade: Alright, good, you got it for me, alright.
David Mendenhall: Got it. Alright, Treant.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, can I just add the Enclave Warriors?
Wade: Yeah, sure.
David Mendenhall: Huh?
Kostadis Roussos: Yep, just let me… let me just add…
David Mendenhall: 313.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, that's not how many, that's, you know… 13 and 16.
David Mendenhall: Sorry, what is… I don't know what you meant, but… oh, I see.
David Mendenhall: AC16.
David Mendenhall: AC13.
Kostadis Roussos: So the dexterity was 3. But.
David Mendenhall: You want to roll initiatives for them?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I'm gonna roll initiatives for them, give me…
David Mendenhall: They can join next round, I assume?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: I will just… we will skip over them until, after Vukradin ends that.
David Mendenhall: Makes sense.
David Mendenhall: Until after Valphine.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, I don't know why it's doing this to me, but…
David Mendenhall: No.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
David Mendenhall: Okay, so… Treant is up.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Treant is up. So you didn't free the other guy, right? Is that why the other guy's not good?
Wade: Hey, guy of life.
David Mendenhall: But there's still nobody in the Whispering Grove.
Kostadis Roussos: Well.
Wade: Yeah, we're staying on the outsides.
Kostadis Roussos: You're staying on the outsides, over these… these two guys are in the grove, so the tree ant…
Kostadis Roussos: Is pissed.
Kostadis Roussos: And… What?
David Mendenhall: Why is he pissed?
Wade: Because the guys are in his grove.
Kostadis Roussos: The guys are in his grove, and they're trying to… and they're trying to…
David Mendenhall: Number 1, ELF1.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, and Lyra.
David Mendenhall: Oh, Lyra's not.
Wade: outside of the garage.
David Mendenhall: outside, but ELF1 is inside. I agree.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, the grove is the circle around the trees.
David Mendenhall: Oh.
Kostadis Roussos: So, as long as you're close to touching the trees, you're okay.
David Mendenhall: Oh, I see, I see.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, sorry, shouldn't.
David Mendenhall: Not touching a tree. Got it.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, and he screams, you think I'm wrong! You think there is something wrong with me! That I must be changed back!
Kostadis Roussos: I am… and starts spewing all sorts of stuff about how he's happy to be powerful and dangerous, and, like, people should respect his choices.
Gary Young: Well, conveniently.
David Mendenhall: I have pro respect…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so he takes, he, he, he slams the guy most sneak next to you. Does his?
David Mendenhall: Uncle Warrior, yeah, he's not gonna last long.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
David Mendenhall: field number one.
Kostadis Roussos: Shield number 1 gets hit twice.
David Mendenhall: It does, so Beat Shield number one might be no more.
Wade: Bye.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, well…
Wade: He did his job.
Kostadis Roussos: Takes 15 points of damage, he's down to 1 hit point.
David Mendenhall: Oh, oh, baby, that's perfect!
Wade: It's perfect, he takes one… attack.
David Mendenhall: Oh, he'll have to lead up another round, I love it! Alright, Brewbarry, you're up, man.
Gary Young: Action economy.
David Mendenhall: Actual good news, for once.
Kostadis Roussos: Like, seriously?
David Mendenhall: So, remind me about… If he didn't die? Of course that's good news!
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, no, I'm just sorry. It's… it's… I'm just, like, going that he didn't die, I'm, like, going, wait, you're… you're a redshirt, you're supposed to die, it's supposed to be this dramatic.
Gary Young: Am I allowed to stand here?
David Mendenhall: On game.
Gary Young: What is this well thing again?
Kostadis Roussos: That's one of the planar wells.
Gary Young: So I don't want to stand on it, is what you're saying?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, but if you stand on it, you risk, you know, madness.
Gary Young: You mean more than I am already?
David Mendenhall: You don't want to go do the ritual?
David Mendenhall: You don't want to do rituals? Do the rituals.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: You can run to try a ritual.
David Mendenhall: Oh, I guess if you're raging, then you'd need to attack.
Gary Young: Yeah, I need to attack.
Wade: Yeah, you and I will keep the brambles down.
Gary Young: Can I stand on this well?
Kostadis Roussos: No. These are… these are all the wells, these are… I just didn't use the same icon for them. So, one is 4x…
Kostadis Roussos: But you can say…
Gary Young: to, like, stand here.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Gary Young: Wow. Being large is some disadvantages.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on, hold on.
Kostadis Roussos: You must roll a Wisdom saving throw.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Gary Young: Wisdom, you say.
Wade: Oh, wow. With a minus one, even.
David Mendenhall: Barbarians always make their wisdom say.
Wade: We're insane, dude.
Kostadis Roussos: Have you told him about the other barbarian?
Kostadis Roussos: we played Curse of Strahd, and the Barbarian… I kept trying… Strahd kept trying to command the Barbarian, and he kept getting, like, 18, 19, and 20.
David Mendenhall: Good times.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, alright. Okay. Okay, so you do not, get… Alright.
Gary Young: I don't get… suspicious thing. Okay, great.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Gary Young: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: There's an aura, so hold on, let me just draw the aura for you guys.
Gary Young: You, you hadn't yet entered the aura.
Kostadis Roussos: So now that you have entered it for the first time, I should probably draw it out.
Wade: Around the triumph…
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Wade: You can just apply it to the token, can't you?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, yeah, that's right. Sorry, why didn't I think of that?
Wade: Like that, like on Soma?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: There.
Kostadis Roussos: That's the aura.
Gary Young: What state were?
Wade: I don't see it, though, unfortunately.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, you don't?
Kostadis Roussos: Maybe because it's the wrong… I chose the worst possible color.
Kostadis Roussos: How about now?
Gary Young: No.
Wade: No, that's weird.
Kostadis Roussos: Really?
Wade: Yeah.
Wade: Well, I… it was worth a shot.
David Mendenhall: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, hold on.
David Mendenhall: You can just tell us. It's alright.
Wade: Okay, there we see, yeah, that, I mean, that works.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, that works.
Wade: Well, it just vanished.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I know, I just need to get the right… no, this is the wrong one. Alright, so we will use this one.
Kostadis Roussos: Maybe we'll use this one here. There's the aura.
David Mendenhall: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Gary Young: Alright, well, I assume 16 hits the vine.
Wade: Mine's are 12, yeah.
Gary Young: So, it takes 14.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. And I get to cleave into the tree in.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, you're gonna cleave into the trance?
Gary Young: Sure.
David Mendenhall: Vine took 14, you said?
Gary Young: Yeah.
David Mendenhall: But you're attacking the wrong vine. The vine… the vine you need to attack is on the other side of the tree.
Wade: Well, there's a… there's a dude over here that could use.
David Mendenhall: Oh, that, that, that one. Oh, okay, so we need to track both now.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, but you're also… oh, nope, you're not, you're still 10 feet away.
Wade: Yeah, he can't hit the… he can't hit the one that Soma's chewing on.
Kostadis Roussos: Actually, he can. No, he can.
Wade: That's nice.
David Mendenhall: 12, 15 and 12.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Done. Okay.
Gary Young: I wouldn't be able to cleave into the… into the tree. So, does a 12 hit the tree?
Kostadis Roussos: The, the, the, the, with the trend, or the.
Wade: Triage is a 16.
Gary Young: That's a trillion. Okay, alright.
Kostadis Roussos: That's actually 15, sorry, did I… was it… did I put 16? 16 right?
David Mendenhall: I've seen in there. I'm just going by with you right in the…
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, no, it is 15, 15, it is 15, sorry, my bad.
David Mendenhall: Alright, I believe Blue Cross…
Kostadis Roussos: the intern.
Kostadis Roussos: 16.
Kostadis Roussos: Sorry, I was looking at the wrong thing, 16.
David Mendenhall: Is it 16? It was 16. Alright, are we ready?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, Cas?
Wade: Still need a Valphine.
David Mendenhall: Nope, she… oh, yeah, okay, Valphine, okay, yeah?
Gary Young: Alright, so I'll come down here, so I'm still kind of, like, outside, right?
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, you're outside of the range, but you're now inside of the grove.
Wade: I'll stay touching the trees!
Kostadis Roussos: You stay in the trees here, not inside the groves.
Gary Young: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So, if you're on one of the squares where there's tree or outside the grove.
Kostadis Roussos: From the perspective… from the perspective of this trend.
Gary Young: So should Brewbarry not have gone inside?
Wade: No, he can pass all his wisdom saves, he's good.
Gary Young: Yeah, what could possibly go wrong? Okay.
Gary Young: So, Valphine… I believe we actually need to try this, fairy fire again.
Gary Young: I don't know.
Wade: Fair guiding bolts.
Wade: Oh, Guiding Bolt or Fairy Fire?
Gary Young: Fairy Fire is a concentration, so, and it affects multiple, so…
Wade: Probably a good idea.
Gary Young: It's superior.
Kostadis Roussos: I blew the second row.
Gary Young: But I need to make sure that I have it as a spell, and not just as a…
Gary Young: An ability, and for some reason, the scroll bar is not working very well for me.
Gary Young: You're welcome.
Wade: cursed.
Gary Young: Elven lineage spells cast as a spell slot.
Kostadis Roussos: Which means you can cast them whenever you want, I guess?
Gary Young: Okay.
Gary Young: So… First label, evocation, yeah.
Gary Young: That should do.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so I blew the saving throw, so he's, he's covered in his little green thing.
Gary Young: So it is, affecting enemies and a radius.
Gary Young: Ayy… 20 foot cube.
Gary Young: So… 20 foot cube is…
Kostadis Roussos: There's only one bad guy, so that doesn't… it's not really that compli… I mean, other than the trees.
Gary Young: Can I not get the vine stew?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so the vines are covered, and the trans.
Gary Young: Okay, so we have advantage.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: you have advantage. It's like… Alright, we're done with Valphine, right?
Gary Young: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: The Enclave Warrior. Alright.
David Mendenhall: Yes, I'm sorry.
Kostadis Roussos: The Enclave Warrior…
David Mendenhall: actually gave you a SkyMaster confidence.
Kostadis Roussos: Rolls his saving throw, and manages to not get impacted.
Kostadis Roussos: And it goes 1, 2, 3, 4…
Kostadis Roussos: What does he do?
Kostadis Roussos: He will, shoot with his bow.
Kostadis Roussos: and miss.
David Mendenhall: Why isn't he trying to help with the ritual?
Kostadis Roussos: Because he's got one hit point. If he stays in the area, he will die from the… and blows the saving throw, he will die.
David Mendenhall: Huh.
Kostadis Roussos: So… and he noticed that you guys.
David Mendenhall: You really need to complete the ritual. It's, you know, he should be, you know, he should be doing…
Kostadis Roussos: Are you asking him that? Because there is an answer that is not snarky.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, I don't understand. I'm gonna go work on the ritual, I'll probably get obliterated.
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, no, no, he goes, no, you don't understand. If we kill… since when we showed up.
Kostadis Roussos: The treant was weak, now it is powerful, but if we… now altogether, we can gang up on the treant and kill it, and then perform the ritual sealing the planar rift. We don't have to…
David Mendenhall: But if we seal the rift, it doesn't matter if the tree ends alive or dead.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, but, I'm gonna seal the breath. Okay. Whose turn is it?
Kostadis Roussos: I believe it's yours.
Kostadis Roussos: Lyra's like, are you sure?
David Mendenhall: I'm sure.
Kostadis Roussos: Vukradin, you introduce yourself, right?
David Mendenhall: Yes, there's a failure.
David Mendenhall: One failure down.
Kostadis Roussos: Does anybody want to help him?
Wade: And, which one were you doing?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, she has…
Wade: Oh, sleight of hand? Yeah, I'm not particularly useful at that. You should get somebody better.
David Mendenhall: I think it's just if you… is help take an action?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh yeah, it is, alright, the LA is. I'm just trying to see.
David Mendenhall: Failure. I love it. One failure down.
Kostadis Roussos: Good to go.
Kostadis Roussos: Lyra turns to you and says, do you know what you're doing with this ritual?
David Mendenhall: yes, I am doing my plus 6 proficient
David Mendenhall: roll, and I am failing it.
David Mendenhall: Would you like me to do the plus 2 instead?
Kostadis Roussos: She goes, no need to be snippy.
Kostadis Roussos: We're all in this together. Go team intervention. All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Lucrative. Alright, the Blighted Vine.
Kostadis Roussos: None of the bladder.
David Mendenhall: cannot perform the same action twice in a row. Well, that's gonna suck. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Soma, Europe.
Wade: Blighted Vine doesn't do anything?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, oh, you are within range of the blood, I didn't notice that.
David Mendenhall: Don't I? I should, like, take some damage, because I moved… Would you stop rolling so high on me?
Kostadis Roussos: Can I take some damage, because I, like, went into… Yeah, roll a D… roll a D20.
David Mendenhall: Is it a save, or it's just a D20?
Kostadis Roussos: role as saving throw DEC12 Wisdom.
David Mendenhall: Failed.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, druids are… bards are curious. Alright,
Kostadis Roussos: Okay… And… you have disadvantage on your next attack roll.
David Mendenhall: Okay, well, probably not going to be attacking anything, so that won't be a problem.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, we have minus 3 takeaway points.
David Mendenhall: Minus 3 hit points? Yes. Someone… someone took 5 hit points away from me, was…
David Mendenhall: Or maybe that was… maybe that was, last week. Okay.
Wade: It might have been.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: None.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, who's next?
Wade: It was the vines, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Soma, you're up.
Wade: Are the Vines hit me?
Kostadis Roussos: 4 points of damage.
Wade: Alright, so it takes me down to 24.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Wade: Oh, where the HP current on Soma? 24… Alright,
Wade: So Ferry Fire is on these guys.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Wade: Alright, that should make this a little less embarrassing.
Wade: Advantage roll… Alright.
Wade: That's, 12 damn, or no?
Kostadis Roussos: 13 points of damage.
Wade: 13, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: That's enough to have knocked it out.
Wade: Oh, I think I misread my other one, plus critical, yeah.
Wade: Whatever.
Wade: That guy was at 12 hit points, right? So he dead?
Kostadis Roussos: Yep, he's dead.
Wade: Alright.
Wade: So, let's go ahead and scribble those out, or whatever.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, yes, let me just do that.
Wade: And so now, this guy is free number 2, I assume?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, he's free.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on, I have to scribble this guy as well.
Wade: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Wade: And then I have, one more attack, and I may as well, I'm just gonna enter the doom Zone.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright?
Wade: It's a wisdom saving throw, is it?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, what's what I'm saying, Carl.
Wade: Alright, let me pull up the right character sheet… Are you shitting me?
David Mendenhall: Oh wait, don't I have something that I can't get less than a 10, or something like that?
Kostadis Roussos: I think so.
Kostadis Roussos: I thought there was… I thought you had one of those.
David Mendenhall: Something like that.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah, we talked about.
David Mendenhall: Only if it's a charisma check.
Wade: Yeah, it's like your performance checks or something like that.
David Mendenhall: Only charisma checks.
Wade: Alright, what happens when I miss my saving throw here?
Kostadis Roussos: You take, 3 points of damage, and…
Wade: 3? Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: And a disadvantage for your next attack.
Wade: But the tree ant has Fairy Fire.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Wade: So they cancel each other out?
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Wade: parent.
Kostadis Roussos: Oot.
Wade: Alright, so I did a… bite, so then the tree ant gets the claws… And it misses.
Kostadis Roussos: Clive Warrior.
Kostadis Roussos: 2… I wonder what creature it thinks has that many endpoints.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Wade: Next up will be Trent.
Kostadis Roussos: Hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Treant goes, Why do you attack me? I… I am but a… I am but a feature of the natural world.
Kostadis Roussos: Lyra shouts, You are not, you are a planar abomination.
Kostadis Roussos: Nutrient.
Kostadis Roussos: So, after she says that to him.
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, You wish to send me back to where I came from?
Kostadis Roussos: She goes, you do not belong here.
Kostadis Roussos: So, he, first, he uses a bonus action to trap her.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so she needs to make a second throw.
Kostadis Roussos: And she is snared by the treant.
Kostadis Roussos: And then he turns to, I will kill your friends!
Kostadis Roussos: And he attacks the…
Kostadis Roussos: Oh my gosh, I rolled the 1.
Kostadis Roussos: And then I rolled a 10. I will do not do none of those things. Lyra shouts. You're planar abomin- you planar abomination! You have warped the treant that used to guard this forest.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Who's next?
Gary Young: Premier.
Kostadis Roussos: Ruger.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on, let me… let me add the… hold on, if we're… yeah, not… okay, Brewbarry, you're up.
Gary Young: Alright, I'm attacking the last vine.
Gary Young: And I will do it with my fancy thing.
Gary Young: 7 damage.
Gary Young: on the vine.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, it's got 8 hit points left.
Wade: Did you forget your advantage, for what it's worth?
Gary Young: I did. Good point.
Wade: Crit? I don't know.
Wade: Alright, well.
Wade: It's worth a shot.
Gary Young: And then cleave into the trance.
Gary Young: Which is a 24 to hits.
Gary Young: Damage on the train.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on, I'm trying to think.
Kostadis Roussos: So, you have advantage.
Kostadis Roussos: But it's able to create disadvantage as a bonus reaction to one attack by suddenly shifting unnaturally in the planar winds.
Gary Young: So you don't…
Kostadis Roussos: So your first attack, you don't get advantage on that attack, that's my only point.
Gary Young: Okay, well, I did not need Advantage to head.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So, how much damage did you do?
Gary Young: I applied at 12.
Kostadis Roussos: Great.
Kostadis Roussos: 12. The tree aunt is very annoyed.
Gary Young: Alright, Valphine, you're up.
Gary Young: Valphine is still concentrating, and then she will use her crossbow on this vine, try to finish this thing off.
Gary Young: And that's an 18 hit for 4 damage?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Gary Young: Which is… not quite enough.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: And, Lyra. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Lyra… what does Lyra do?
Kostadis Roussos: Lyra looks at the creature and says.
Kostadis Roussos: This has gone on long enough.
Kostadis Roussos: This has gone on long enough, and she…
Kostadis Roussos: What does she do? She casts Moonbean.
Kostadis Roussos: She casts Moonbeam.
Kostadis Roussos: Where's it?
Kostadis Roussos: Five Ford Circle Moonbean, right?
Wade: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: Next, we cast Moonbeam.
Kostadis Roussos: And, the third.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so it's the second level spell…
Kostadis Roussos: Fourth level… 4th level, moon… second level spell, Moonbeam.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so it's, 2D10 points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, unless she makes the same throw, so 2D10…
Kostadis Roussos: So, 7 points of damage.
Wade: And she puts the cylinder down somewhere.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, did I… oh, I think.
Wade: I guess since things aren't moving, it doesn't really matter, it's just gonna sit on the tree.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I think I could have chosen a color that was not green.
Kostadis Roussos: I don't know if you guys can see the 5-foot circle, but it's kind of…
Wade: We don't, but it's on top of the tree end, I assume, because there's nothing else.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Wade: That's Lyra, the Enclave guys…
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, alright. So Lyra did her action…
Kostadis Roussos: And so we now sort again.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm gonna play Warrior 1, alright. He will,
Kostadis Roussos: He will shoot an arrow to try to help his buddy across the… across the way.
Wade: Don't forget the advantage!
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, 20-20, keep buying one.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, he hits.
Wade: Yeah. Two 19ths.
Kostadis Roussos: For 4 points of damage.
Gary Young: That's just enough.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Wade: Everybody's free!
Kostadis Roussos: And Clive Warrior number 3 is free.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Gordon, you're up.
David Mendenhall: Okay… Let's see here… we've got…
Wade: Is Blighted Vine at 4 hit points? No.
David Mendenhall: Now it's zero. It's zero.
David Mendenhall: They're all…
Kostadis Roussos: They're all gone.
David Mendenhall: Treant at 98, I have disadvantage on attack rolls. Brewbarry's got plenty of hit points.
David Mendenhall: Aww.
Gary Young: Vintage, but very firm.
Kostadis Roussos: You also have to make your saving throw for… if you stay… if you end your turn, you have to make a saving throw.
Kostadis Roussos: Against the psychotic, psychic, madness.
David Mendenhall: Oh, but I already have dis… oh, this would be on top of the disadvantage? This would be, like, it would get even worse?
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, you just get that… it's the saving throw versus damage.
David Mendenhall: I just…
Wade: 3 hit points.
David Mendenhall: Oh, I take that, Dan, that 3.
Gary Young: Did I miss a saving throw that I was supposed to do?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, you'll miss the same duration, too.
Gary Young: Wisdom, huh?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, okay, you made your savings, I believe?
Gary Young: 13, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: I think he did.
David Mendenhall: Hmm… Can I move here?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, DC12 is a, is a…
David Mendenhall: Can I… can I move now?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I'm sorry, I was talking to… I was talking to Gary. Yes, you can move there.
David Mendenhall: 16? Oof, that is tough.
David Mendenhall: I guess… has the treant been doing much damage?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, when it hits, it does a lot of damage.
David Mendenhall: Alright, I guess I'll try Command-Halt on the… Try command on the tramp.
Kostadis Roussos: Damn. Wisdom save.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, wisdom saved.
Kostadis Roussos: I rolled it and said…
David Mendenhall: Drake it?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, I rolled a 7.
David Mendenhall: Of course you did. Alright.
David Mendenhall: Yep, I will go back to waiting for my turn.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Wade: I think a drop form?
Wade: I believe Wild Shape…
Kostadis Roussos: Right?
Wade: Pull my normal me in…
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Wade: And then it leaves me… what was that? I was 21, so…
Wade: And I'm going to,
Wade: Use the ritual. The Wisdom Nature one.
David Mendenhall: We should probably wait on that, so that we can do, have advantage on all attempts.
Wade: I have advantage on this anyway.
David Mendenhall: Oh, okay, alright.
Wade: Nate is part of the staff, so…
David Mendenhall: Alright, sure, why not?
Wade: Why not indeed? So…
Wade: Just a wisdom save, wisdom throw?
David Mendenhall: Let's do check, yeah.
Wade: Alright, I beat the 15.
Kostadis Roussos: She did it.
Wade: I beat it twice.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
David Mendenhall: That's 1… 1 and 1.
Wade: 1 and 1.
Kostadis Roussos: Litera shouts, be careful if you make any mistakes… any more mistakes might provoke… might cause…
Kostadis Roussos: Bad things to happen.
David Mendenhall: Oh, I believe it.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: So… And she applauds your… she says she's very happy, and she goes, huzzah!
Wade: Alright.
Wade: I think that's the only act… that takes the entire action, right? And my bonus action was to drop form, for that matter, so…
Kostadis Roussos: seconds.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Gary Young: So, treatment?
Wade: Hi, Lyra! I'm not a bear.
Kostadis Roussos: Lyra goes, you're a druid as well.
Kostadis Roussos: Did you make your wisdom saving throw?
Wade: Oh, I have to make one just for the being… ending turn there, don't I? Yeah.
Wade: Well, at least that one sucked, but the one that mattered was okay.
Kostadis Roussos: You're gonna say take 3.4 points of damage.
Wade: 4 points or 3?
Kostadis Roussos: 33333.
Wade: Alright, so I'm at 18.
Kostadis Roussos: At 3 points of damage, and, right.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, what does the train do?
Kostadis Roussos: Eeny, meeny, miny, moe… The tree int's really pissed at the Emerald Enclave folks.
Kostadis Roussos: He considers them betrayers of the worst kind.
Kostadis Roussos: So he attacks… One of the two… Guys…
Kostadis Roussos: And, it's 2D6 plus 4…
Kostadis Roussos: So she does 9 points of damage to the second guy.
Kostadis Roussos: And he does.
Kostadis Roussos: And he kills him.
Kostadis Roussos: So, Emerald Enclave person number 2 is there, and he uses his bonus action
Kostadis Roussos: To trap number 3 right where he is, so he can't escape.
David Mendenhall: Who d- who died?
Kostadis Roussos: Number 2.
David Mendenhall: Oh, no.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: He died.
David Mendenhall: I mean… Zero hit points, or dead dead?
Kostadis Roussos: Not 21 hit points. He's dead-dead.
David Mendenhall: Oh, we don't play with that. Alright, he's.
Kostadis Roussos: What's… what am I doing?
Kostadis Roussos: He's at zero headpoints.
Kostadis Roussos: Blue as death saved. How about that?
David Mendenhall: Number 2? Okay, the tracker's not getting updated. Okay. 2, is it 0?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: There we go. Two is at zero. One death saved. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Who's next?
Kostadis Roussos: Brewbarry, you're up.
Gary Young: Okay.
Gary Young: I am… we only have the treant left, yes?
Gary Young: Alright.
Gary Young: So no cleaving, so we'll just go with this.
Gary Young: Here, and I will…
Kostadis Roussos: advantage.
Gary Young: Why do I not get advantage?
Kostadis Roussos: Because he can deflect one of the attacks, though he attempts to deflect the first one.
Kostadis Roussos: You would normally have disadvantage.
Gary Young: Okay.
Gary Young: Alright, so then I have to do a save?
Kostadis Roussos: Because…
Gary Young: Can take 3 points of damage.
Gary Young: 3 points of damage.
Gary Young: What type of damage?
Kostadis Roussos: psychic. Psychic, psychic, yeah.
Gary Young: Alright.
Gary Young: Okay. Enclave Warrior 2.
Kostadis Roussos: Enclave Warrior 2, he's, takes a death save.
Kostadis Roussos: He fails his second death save.
David Mendenhall: He's had 2 failures?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
David Mendenhall: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Right?
David Mendenhall: Valphine?
Kostadis Roussos: Fina.
Wade: Graffina.
Gary Young: Should I save this, save this dude?
David Mendenhall: I was gonna use my action to save him, since, like, my attacks are useless. Why don't you let me save him?
Gary Young: I don't know that my attacks are any more effective, but…
David Mendenhall: I think they will be.
Gary Young: You think so?
Wade: Oh, when the tree had finished his turn in the Moonbeam, didn't he need to take more damage?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, yes, yes, thank you, thank you, thank you.
Kostadis Roussos: Thank you.
Kostadis Roussos: He blew his saving throw, so it would be 10.
Wade: Can we stack Moonbeams?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah?
David Mendenhall: I think you can.
Kostadis Roussos: Who knows?
David Mendenhall: But you can only concentrate on one spell at a time.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, yes, but I haven't cast my Moonbeam yet.
David Mendenhall: Oh, perfect.
Kostadis Roussos: 2 Druids. 18 points of damage.
David Mendenhall: She's down to 80.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
David Mendenhall: Alright, that's good.
Kostadis Roussos: Turns out, do you know what… we know what the most deadliest combo is? Two wizards who cast Firewall.
Kostadis Roussos: wall of fire.
Wade: How is that so deadly?
Kostadis Roussos: Because you can get them this way and that way.
Kostadis Roussos: And you can occupy a much bigger area of effect.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, well, fire's pretty cool.
Kostadis Roussos: And then… and then if you could do Firestorm, it's even crazier with two high-level clerics.
Gary Young: Should I assume the train has a bad, reflex save?
Kostadis Roussos: That's awesome.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, it's a tree with interdimensional capabilities.
David Mendenhall: No.
Gary Young: Dope.
David Mendenhall: Not assume that.
Kostadis Roussos: You, you can try.
Gary Young: Alright, we'll try it.
Kostadis Roussos: Great. What are you gonna try?
Gary Young: Sacred Flame for 8.
Gary Young: DC.
Kostadis Roussos: Actually, it actually is not a bad idea, because it has a minus 1, so it takes 8 points of damage.
Gary Young: Alright, I'll play that.
Gary Young: Okay, next is Lyra.
Kostadis Roussos: Moira.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: You know what?
Kostadis Roussos: What does Lyra do?
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Why,
Kostadis Roussos: Lyra… Pass… so she turns to the bard. Are you going to heal my… are you going to heal
Kostadis Roussos: She points to, Emerald Enclave number 2.
Kostadis Roussos: Can anyone heal him?
David Mendenhall: Yeah, yeah, I'll take care of them.
Kostadis Roussos: Excellent, so she goes, in that case, Die, you creature of evil!
Kostadis Roussos: hits him with a sacred… with a Guiding Volt.
Gary Young: Creature of non-neutrality.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Heading. Bolt.
Kostadis Roussos: 8.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so what is the first… what is the first level guy involved,
Kostadis Roussos: It's a 4d6 worth of damage. Yeah, she's gonna use her second slot, she's gonna use that, so it's 5d6.
David Mendenhall: 5d6.
Kostadis Roussos: 15 points of damage.
David Mendenhall: Nice.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
David Mendenhall: Grant is down to… 57.
Wade: And is, guiding bolted, right?
David Mendenhall: Yeah, so he…
Wade: Double advantage!
Kostadis Roussos: Doesn't work that way.
David Mendenhall: You already have an advantage, but yeah. Enclave Warrior 3?
Kostadis Roussos: Enclave Warrior 3, Enclave Warrior 3 got freed this round, so we have to see… we do it, he starts the next round.
David Mendenhall: Okay, she's no longer trapped.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, I'm gonna…
David Mendenhall: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Warrior One.
Kostadis Roussos: Enclave Warrior… Enclave Warrior 1…
David Mendenhall: Nope.
Kostadis Roussos: Shoots an arrow… and hits…
Kostadis Roussos: Or 4 points of damage against the Treant.
David Mendenhall: Alright.
Gary Young: I've got it.
David Mendenhall: Make query.
David Mendenhall: Alright, Vukradin.
David Mendenhall: As, how much movement?
David Mendenhall: 30 feet.
David Mendenhall: 5, 10, 15, 20…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
David Mendenhall: The number of hit points equal to your level?
David Mendenhall: That is 3.
David Mendenhall: Oh, it's free.
Wade: Hey, it's 3 more than he had.
David Mendenhall: He now has 3 hit points.
Kostadis Roussos: It's very grateful.
David Mendenhall: instead of 0, and I can drag him, I assume?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
David Mendenhall: So if I go there, then he would go next to me, outside the screen?
David Mendenhall: Thank you.
Kostadis Roussos: He says, thank you, thank you!
David Mendenhall: I can do things that don't involve saving throws.
David Mendenhall: They're much more effective. Soma.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
Wade: So much.
Gary Young: Film has a vintage.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, swimming, you're up.
Wade: Yeah, we're just gonna start stacking the moonbeams, so…
David Mendenhall: loving it.
Wade: Let's throw them dice…
Kostadis Roussos: I blew my saving throw.
Wade: Good, you can take 15 more damage now, and probably another 15 at the end of your turn.
Wade: Well, 15 times… well, we'll see what it comes out to, but yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Great.
Wade: So that is, 38 left.
Kostadis Roussos: Enclave Warrior No. 3 is currently trapped by the… nutrients.
Wade: I assume I need to make a saving throw, because I'm still in the.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
David Mendenhall: And then if you take damage, you…
Wade: I do not.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright?
David Mendenhall: There it is.
Kostadis Roussos: We do not have to deal with the Constitution.
David Mendenhall: You don't have to do a concert.
Kostadis Roussos: Don't say…
David Mendenhall: Concentration.
Kostadis Roussos: So the trend is really pissed.
Kostadis Roussos: You moved one of his guns.
David Mendenhall: It'd be his last round, too.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so he's gonna attack Soma.
Wade: And I'm back up to 17AC now, let's go!
Wade: Alright, I'm gonna be back on chat. Yeah, you whiffed.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, and he attacks again.
David Mendenhall: Another whiff.
Wade: Come on, you can't hit a turtle.
David Mendenhall: Wow.
Kostadis Roussos: Just for the record, I had not…
David Mendenhall: Your luck is finally running out, Quesadas.
Kostadis Roussos: Asset is finally running out.
Wade: Alright, now you've got two moonbeams to, roll for.
Kostadis Roussos: In… 11. The first one is a… I make the first one, but I blow the second one.
Kostadis Roussos: So, Lyra's Moonbeam is… 2D10, alright, you can roll, it'll be your moonbeam.
Wade: It doesn't matter.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, I mean, I know, it is your moonbeat, because it's the second round.
Kostadis Roussos: It's the second one.
Wade: It's alright, 8. Beautiful.
Kostadis Roussos: 8.75.
Wade: 30.
Kostadis Roussos: We got this.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
David Mendenhall: Mike?
Kostadis Roussos: Brewbarry.
Wade: Brewbarry?
Gary Young: Did we deduct the damage on the tree anyhow?
Wade: Yeah, he's at 30 out of whatever.
David Mendenhall: 30.
Wade: At 100 million.
Gary Young: Alright then, we'll just, smash it again.
Gary Young: That would be a hit for 10.
Gary Young: No advantage correct.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Gary Young: Alright.
Gary Young: Next is… who?
Gary Young: is Unclean Warrior 2.
Kostadis Roussos: Enclave Warrior 2… Hey, Mrs. Bo hits for 4 points of damage.
Gary Young: Okay, I got it.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, and he goes over here.
Kostadis Roussos: Valphine, Europe.
Gary Young: Conor, she is going to… Do her… crossbow…
Kostadis Roussos: No, we're gonna do the Sacred Flame.
Kostadis Roussos: Excuse me.
Gary Young: DC13 decks.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you see 13 decks?
Kostadis Roussos: Right, I have to roll my settings around.
Kostadis Roussos: I made my saving throw.
Gary Young: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: make my saving throws, but I can't hit for… I can't hit the save, alright. Lyra…
Kostadis Roussos: Well, once again, we'll use a guiding bolt, and this time it is an S.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Enclave Warrior number 1.
Kostadis Roussos: Where's his bow?
Kostadis Roussos: It's for 3 points of dam- 4 points of damage.
Gary Young: 4 points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: recruited in Europe.
David Mendenhall: Huh.
David Mendenhall: Okay… I no longer have disadvantage.
David Mendenhall: What should I do?
David Mendenhall: I should miss.
Kostadis Roussos: Ouch.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
David Mendenhall: I'm good at that.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: you know, you had a character who would hit all the time, but you got bored of rolling dice and hitting all the time, so now you have… Yes, I am hitting.
David Mendenhall: I am kind of getting bored of this one, though.
David Mendenhall: Let's keep going.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
David Mendenhall: I'm getting kind of bored of the combats.
Wade: Yeah, I don't know,
Wade: Thornwhip, I guess? What was the…
Wade: Oh, no, poison spray, yeah, that was the best cantrip I had, let's go.
Wade: 9 more damage on him.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Wade: That takes him to 3… Dang.
Wade: Well, maybe the Enclave Warrior can finish them.
Kostadis Roussos: How much should you, how many each damage should you do? 9?
Wade: Nine.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so then, does the Unclined Warrior destroy him?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, he dies, yay!
Kostadis Roussos: He's dead.
Kostadis Roussos: The creation.
Wade: It said the tree on the 16, isn't it? Anyway.
Kostadis Roussos: No, but I've got a plus 4 to hit.
Wade: Oh, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: That's kind of what I was doing. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: And map. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: We're around, here we go.
Kostadis Roussos: There we go.
Kostadis Roussos: Total.
David Mendenhall: So, the save that you made…
David Mendenhall: Wade, what, what, which one did you do?
Wade: It was in nature which adds advantage to the next Arcana check, intelligence.
David Mendenhall: Who has the best, intelligence?
Wade: I'm only a plus one.
David Mendenhall: I only have a plus one for me.
Gary Young: Brewbarry.
Wade: Brewbarry can't low anything… roll anything less than a 17 on his wisdom or intellect.
David Mendenhall: What about, Lyra?
Kostadis Roussos: You're, she's got a plus zero.
Wade: Well, it's gonna be any of us with a plus one. Go for it, Dave.
Wade: You got advantage.
David Mendenhall: Sure, why not?
Wade: Doesn't matter who rolls it at this point.
David Mendenhall: I think it does matter.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, well…
Wade: You want me to just roll it, then?
Wade: Here.
Gary Young: Told you.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
David Mendenhall: Two failures.
Wade: Well, that's not good. We're, gonna run into the bad sort of this condition. Alright.
David Mendenhall: Can't win all the quests.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Wade: I try.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Since none of you decided to be away from this…
Kostadis Roussos: Everybody but Valphine, Soma, and Emerald Enclave 1 need to make a saving throw.
Gary Young: What kind?
Kostadis Roussos: A Psychic Blast.
Gary Young: So, wisdom?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, Wisdom saving throws.
Wade: everybody butts?
David Mendenhall: Killed it.
Gary Young: Feeled it worse.
David Mendenhall: Am I dead yet?
Kostadis Roussos: No.
David Mendenhall: Damn it.
Kostadis Roussos: 7 points of damage.
Wade: Why was Soma immune?
Kostadis Roussos: No, Nesoma does not. She doesn't need to make the same throw.
Wade: Why does she… why doesn't she need to make it? I'm just curious.
Kostadis Roussos: Because she's out of range.
Wade: Damn? Oh, alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, no, no, I'm sorry, I thought… I was looking at the bear.
Wade: Oh yeah, the bear is… I'm not bear, like…
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, yeah, so you need to make the same throw as well.
Wade: Yeah, okay, I mean, not that I want to, but…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Is that your third failure, or second failure? No, that's your second failure.
Wade: That was our second failure on this, yeah.
David Mendenhall: Yeah.
David Mendenhall: Okay.
Wade: How much.
David Mendenhall: right now.
Wade: How much damage is it? 7 damage to everyone who failed?
David Mendenhall: We've got one success and 2 failures.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Lyra, you know.
Kostadis Roussos: Lyra looks, this is… this is not good. This is not good.
David Mendenhall: Lyra, was… I just wanna… I was just wondering, like, your plan was to come in here, and you were gonna make these 6…
David Mendenhall: successful ritual actions all on your own. That was your plan?
Wade: With her warrior buddies.
David Mendenhall: Kayla, I'm just asking.
Gary Young: What about the aid?
David Mendenhall: Do you have, do you have, like, good bonuses on these things? Because you… you were going to come in here.
Kostadis Roussos: So…
David Mendenhall: Things are pretty low on these things.
Kostadis Roussos: So, she's like, this looks pretty tricky, is that what you're going to…
David Mendenhall: Yeah, and… yeah, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Did you want to use your charisma to try to get the truth out of her?
David Mendenhall: Oh, sure, why not?
Wade: For 10 minimum, right?
David Mendenhall: It's a 10 minimum on that, so…
David Mendenhall: 15, yep, I got the minimum.
Kostadis Roussos: And what's the silver tongue effect?
David Mendenhall: I'll get a 15. It's the minimum.
David Mendenhall: I got the minimum, 15.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Gary Young: I got an 18.
Kostadis Roussos: Biblihood it is.
David Mendenhall: Fuck you, Valphine. Fuck you.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you want…
Gary Young: Surface fillers are so easy to read.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, just for the record, you're beginning to understand why Valphine's backstory involved her sisters tried to kill her several times.
Gary Young: You know, like, they're easy to figure out.
Kostadis Roussos: Lyra looks at you and goes,
Kostadis Roussos: I don't think I thought this through very carefully.
David Mendenhall: Understatement of the day.
Kostadis Roussos: She goes, Look!
Kostadis Roussos: We heard about this… Rift.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? And there was, you know, there was talk among the umbrella enclave if we should do anything, and some were saying, you know, that we should do nothing, that this was just part of the natural world, and some were saying this was an unnatural act.
Kostadis Roussos: And there was much debate, and I thought this would be, you know, that the planar… these planar disturbances.
David Mendenhall: And if the ritual fails, what's gonna happen?
Wade: Are these natural?
David Mendenhall: This year's looking pretty likely at this point.
Wade: Are they… are you suggesting that this is natural, and you guys are the interventionists that Adabra warned us about?
Kostadis Roussos: She looks at you and goes, yes, I'm… did you… do you mention the name of Adabra or not?
Wade: I do, because I'm just confused. I assumed that they were…
Wade: You know, trying to stop this thing that looks wholly unnatural.
Kostadis Roussos: No, we are interventionists. It's the naturalists who want… who think that this is normal.
Wade: Oh, fuck this, kill her.
Wade: Excuse me.
David Mendenhall: What? No, no, no, no, she's a future fan. We want to be allies with all the parties.
Kostadis Roussos: wait, wait, just… I want to make sure I did not misspeake. Lyra says the planar rift is unnatural.
Kostadis Roussos: And she says, those who think it is natural
Kostadis Roussos: are naturalists, and those who think the planar rift is unnatural and needs to be closed are interventionists.
Wade: Yeah, I gotcha. So, yeah, I'm just gonna throw the third ritual.
David Mendenhall: You're gonna buy it.
Gary Young: In this, help action?
Wade: Huh?
Gary Young: We can use this helpline.
David Mendenhall: You're gonna intentionally fail the saving throw? I'm going to intentionally fail it, yes. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So you've decided… you've decided to ally yourself with the…
Wade: disrupting… The naturalists.
David Mendenhall: proposed.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, who believe that the planar is just part of the natural order.
Wade: Apparently it is.
Kostadis Roussos: That's your go. Okay.
Wade: Actually, I guess before I do that, why don't we use that crazy staff ability I got?
Wade: Where is it? Something about detecting, things.
David Mendenhall: We needed the money, man.
Wade: There was no money for this quest, remember?
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, Adabra was gonna give him some money because she realized that, you know, he needed money. We had that discussion.
Wade: Let's see… Yeah, alright.
Kostadis Roussos: She suddenly realized that your motivation for money is a pure motivation.
David Mendenhall: Funny…
Kostadis Roussos: It's not… it's not for wealth and power, it's to build a music studio.
Wade: Yes, alright, so for the… the staff lets me find unnatural blights and corruptions for a few minutes, so…
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, so…
Wade: Let's use that once… once a day today, right now. What do we got?
Kostadis Roussos: What you get is that, in fact, the…
Kostadis Roussos: Like, all the things that are black, all the… those things are, like, pinging like crazy.
Wade: They're very unnatural.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, so basically, the… from the perspective of me at the staff,
Kostadis Roussos: Let me just… all the things…
Wade: From the perspective of the staff, the interventionists are the naturalists.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Wade: What have you wrought, man?
Wade: Oh, Christ.
Wade: How do I convince Lyra, I guess, of the unnaturalness of all this?
Kostadis Roussos: So I said, no, no, Lyra believes it's unnatural as well.
Wade: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, so just, just to be clear.
Kostadis Roussos: interventionists… Kate, Lehner.
Kostadis Roussos: Stuff.
Kostadis Roussos: And want it out.
Kostadis Roussos: Naturalists.
Kostadis Roussos: C… Planar… Scars as normal.
Wade: And staff sees planar stars as unnatural.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Staff is an interventionist.
Wade: Oh, dear. The staff has betrayed me.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, I mean, you know.
Gary Young: You're a naturalist?
Wade: Thought I was. I don't know anymore.
Kostadis Roussos: Yay!
Wade: I don't know what to believe. I'm going to law school.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, you never really found out what the crux of the debate between the naturalists and the French.
Wade: No, apparently I haven't.
Kostadis Roussos: This is a good time to find out.
Wade: Yeah, no, I, like, what is the deal? What do you think's gonna happen if we close this off, Lyra? Like…
Kostadis Roussos: She… Lyra goes.
Wade: I mean, I don't think we're gonna succeed at this point, but…
Kostadis Roussos: So Lyra says…
Kostadis Roussos: When the War of the Dragons… the end of the War of the Dragons, the Emerald Enclave fractured into two factions.
Wade: Oh, dear.
Kostadis Roussos: One faction believed that Tiamat's survival was an abomination, and needed to be stopped.
Kostadis Roussos: Another faction believed that Tiamat's arrival was part of the natural cycle of things, because wasn't Tiamat part of the natural order of the multiverse?
Kostadis Roussos: And that, in the end, everything would be okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Or would be fine. And so, when several of us decided to go, when the interventionists, when the Emerald Enclave decided to go
Kostadis Roussos: support the armies at the whale of the dragons. The interventionists were outraged and screamed that we had betrayed our calling to preserve natural order.
Kostadis Roussos: when Tiamat was defeated, we all tried to accommodate ourselves and be friendly, but there's still a faction of naturalists who see anyone who tries to make sure that the natural order isn't disrupted by the
Kostadis Roussos: Planar disruptions as inherently violating the natural order.
Kostadis Roussos: And that's, they call us interventionists.
Wade: I mean, this tree is eating people.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, well, since she pauses, Polaris says, trees eating people is, you know, tree… if it is part of the natural order, that, you know, animals eat… but this was not…
Wade: Trees don't eat people. That's not natural in any world.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, and she goes furthermore, these… she points to the wells and to the brambles that are very peculiarly animated. The problem with the tree was that that was… this was a good tree. It was a tree that took care
Kostadis Roussos: prospered the forest, but ever since the planar scars emerged, and she points to the wells, it had become poisoned by some extraplanar force.
Gary Young: And the tree used to only eat bad people.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, yes. The tree… the tree used… she turns to you and says, the tree used to be sustained by sunlight.
Wade: It used to be.
Gary Young: normal.
Wade: tree.
Gary Young: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, and as a result of this planar shift, it had become… it was being sustained by interdimensional energies.
Gary Young: But sunlight is kind of unnatural.
Wade: I don't…
Kostadis Roussos: You would know.
David Mendenhall: to you.
Kostadis Roussos: Leela looks at you as if you're speaking some foreign language that she.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, me too.
Kostadis Roussos: So, okay, so just to help you weigh, just to get, you know, Emerald Enclave, two groups.
Wade: Yeah, no, this is… this just can't be. Like, there's naturalists, and then there's, like, just rolling over and letting the world get excluded.
David Mendenhall: Remember that, remember that, that deer we met, and how out of sorts he felt, and…
Wade: He didn't seem.
David Mendenhall: You know, we should help him. He wanted help, we should help him.
Wade: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: So…
Wade: Let's try to clear this out.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, we're gonna try to clear it out.
David Mendenhall: It's okay, we're gonna fail anyway.
Wade: We're gonna fail anyway.
David Mendenhall: I'm glad you did the right thing.
Wade: I… I had the right intention and failed.
David Mendenhall: Go for it, I want to see the failure.
Gary Young: I have to have the right reasons.
Wade: Hold on, so the best…
Wade: I don't know, I have a plus one deck, so let's go with that, huh?
Wade: It'll have no advantage.
David Mendenhall: I could do another dex roll.
Wade: You've taken that action already, huh?
David Mendenhall: But I just can't do it twice in a row.
Wade: Oh, I see.
David Mendenhall: hit a failure. So I could do another sleight of hand.
Wade: Yeah, go for it.
David Mendenhall: I have advantage, right? Yeah. Somebody can help me?
Wade: I'll help. Yeah, I mean, we have infinite actions at the moment, right? So, well, I'll be helping.
David Mendenhall: I made it.
Wade: Alright, so we're 2 and 2…
Kostadis Roussos: You're tuned, too.
Gary Young: What is the deal?
David Mendenhall: We're 2 and 2, alright. It was 13.
Gary Young: Oh, okay, great.
Kostadis Roussos: Wait, do you guys need another… somebody else who has a high DC, is that what you're saying? A high… what do you need? High dexterity?
Wade: For the sleight-of-hand check for DC3.
David Mendenhall: No, my DEX is pretty high, I just…
David Mendenhall: You know, I'm just bad at rolling.
David Mendenhall: Alright, so someone's gotta do an Intelligence or a wisdom, or somebody else could do a DAX, I don't know if somebody else has a good DAX.
Wade: Well, I mean, I can do my sleight of hand, and then I can come back to wisdom.
Gary Young: You said wisdom? Because I've got plus 5 wisdom.
David Mendenhall: Well, then you should do that, with Advantage.
Wade: Yeah.
Gary Young: Wait, is it Wisdom Save, or like a…
Wade: It's a nature… Or whatever, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
David Mendenhall: Wait, it says…
Wade: Nature wisdom. Nature is an intelligence.
David Mendenhall: Nature check, DC15.
Gary Young: Yeah, nature is intelligence.
Wade: No, yeah, that's weird.
Gary Young: doesn't work.
Wade: Your quest log says, nature, wisdom, but nature is intellect.
Kostadis Roussos: Get rid of the… it's either nature or a wisdom check there.
Wade: Oh, you can choose just the raw stat check?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Wade: Oh, okay.
Gary Young: Where I'll start? That would be plus 3.
David Mendenhall: Okay, with Advantage.
David Mendenhall: Go for it.
Gary Young: Plus 3 with advantage, okay.
David Mendenhall: Made it.
David Mendenhall: Okay, so that's 3 and… 3 and 2.
Gary Young: So, like, I've seen these kind of blights in the Underdark, you know, like…
Kostadis Roussos: So you now have advantage on Arcana.
Wade: Well, we'd have advantage anyway, because we're… Yeah, we're kind of…
David Mendenhall: Given that we're all helping each other at this point. So, who wants to… I've got a plus one.
Wade: I'll have to do plus one sleight of hand, I guess.
David Mendenhall: No… It's the lowest… It's not a plus one?
Wade: No, but it… I mean, it's… it'd be wisdom, but my last action was a Wisdom one, or was Nature Wisdom, so…
David Mendenhall: But you can do the.
Wade: That's the thing, like, I want to go to the easiest one with the plus one, because my strongest one is I can't do twice in a row.
David Mendenhall: Correct, yeah.
Wade: Yeah.
Wade: It feels mathematically, like, the only… the best option, which isn't great, but…
David Mendenhall: Oh, that's awful. Alright, we botched it.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on, hold on, hold on, hold on, the Emerald Enclave guy has a plus 7 on stuff.
Wade: Now he tells us, we'd asked him earlier about that.
David Mendenhall: 7 on, bite of hand?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, sleight of hand.
David Mendenhall: Well, we already ruined the ritual, so we knew that was gonna happen.
Wade: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, well, I was gonna… before Soma rolled it, I was gonna have the… you could have one of the arm rolled out.
David Mendenhall: Er, go ahead.
Wade: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: it.
David Mendenhall: We were at 3 and 2.
Wade: Yeah.
Gary Young: Well, I mean, we could just do the same roll.
Kostadis Roussos: So, yes.
David Mendenhall: So now we're at… now we're at 4 and 2, and then we failed, so…
Wade: Yeah, someone's role still causes a failure.
David Mendenhall: We're not gonna get to 6, anyway.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, okay.
Wade: So we're 4 and 3.
Kostadis Roussos: So, unfortunately… the… Area turns into the wells that grow in size.
Kostadis Roussos: The emerald withering grove is now possessed by a planar rift.
Wade: Well, shit.
Wade: I don't think we made the world a better place today, guys.
David Mendenhall: Alright, let's get outta here.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Wade: Yeah, I think it is just kind of a good opportunity to run.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Lyra goes, this, this, this did not work the way I had hoped.
Wade: Well, at least you're alive.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, but…
Wade: We showed up, you were, you know, tree chow.
Kostadis Roussos: But we… the intervention, it was supposed to work. This was going to be a… this was…
Kostadis Roussos: She's very distraught.
Wade: Yeah, well…
David Mendenhall: In my world, where all the checks fail.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm sorry, David.
Wade: Considered nature wanted us to fail these checks.
David Mendenhall: Well, if we had more charisma checks, I might actually pass them.
David Mendenhall: We don't have a lot of charisma checks.
Wade: Now, you can't schmooze a planar existence out of existence.
Kostadis Roussos: As you… as you run away, you see a very curious creature.
Kostadis Roussos: sort of emerge.
Kostadis Roussos: From the… from the planar rift.
Kostadis Roussos: TMX.
Wade: a junior.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, he's kind of like a phased-out creature whose eyes are… Distorted.
Kostadis Roussos: Like, as if he's under control of something, and he's going around
Kostadis Roussos: Essentially, picking things off the ground.
David Mendenhall: Hmm.
Wade: Does anybody want to engage that, or are we just gonna kinda get out of here?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, getting out of Dodge.
Wade: I think it's get-out time.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Gary Young: We could parley.
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, you could try, he's not… he doesn't… he seems to be very… he seems to be not engaging with you guys, and the area… this whole area, not the circular area, is where the whole planar…
Kostadis Roussos: It has grown. It hasn't grown past the edge of this… these wood… these woods.
Wade: While V&A's gonna hang out.
Gary Young: From the edge of the woods, then, I will inspect and see what he's trying to do.
David Mendenhall: I'm leaving.
Kostadis Roussos: None.
David Mendenhall: Kradabra.
Wade: This, this cannot be…
David Mendenhall: Okay, that's fine, feel free.
Kostadis Roussos: He seems to be collecting ingredients.
Gary Young: collecting ingredients.
Gary Young: What are you doing?
Kostadis Roussos: He looks at you and says.
Kostadis Roussos: He looks at you, and you realize that he's not under his own control, that somebody feels like there's a puppet controlling. He's a puppet that's being controlled.
Gary Young: Oh.
Kostadis Roussos: That someone else is in charge. And he goes and collects some more ingredients, and he goes and collects some more ingredients.
Kostadis Roussos: Then he goes and collects some more ingredients. He picks some stuff off the trant, and then he disappears into the well.
Gary Young: Disappears into the well.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Wade: Just, like, dives in.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, just dives in.
Kostadis Roussos: It's almost as if he came here to cultivate something. Something was being cultivated here.
Wade: Put a pin in that.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: And then you run out.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: And it's 10.38.
Wade: Yeah, we're done.
Gary Young: They're still kind of, like, doing their thing. They're still strong.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
Gary Young: The bulls are still doing their planar disruption thing.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, the, the, the, the, the, I'm sorry, what is doing there?
Gary Young: Like, when he went back, it didn't, like, close behind him or anything.
Wade: wells, the wells are still disrupting the world.
Kostadis Roussos: the wells are still disrupting. They're not growing.
Kostadis Roussos: Roll it… roll a nature or investigation, or Arcana check.
Gary Young: These are all minus 1.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, so, Soma, Soma, your nature gets that some… whoever… that some… that these… these planar scars are not accidental, they're obviously…
Kostadis Roussos: Being motivated by it. Somebody's doing them for a purpose.
Wade: Yeah. It's not just random.
Kostadis Roussos: It's not just a random natural event.
Kostadis Roussos: Does anybody want to roll in an investigation?
David Mendenhall: No, I'm already in Phandalin.
Kostadis Roussos: You're like, I'm not… this entire forest thing is just not my thing.
Gary Young: We'll have Brewbarry rural investigation.
Kostadis Roussos: He does not notice anything.
Kostadis Roussos: He notices that everybody has only one side of bread.
Wade: Alright.
Wade: The madness!
Kostadis Roussos: Lyra's, like, really upset. She's like, this was supposed to work.
Kostadis Roussos: We saved your life, your, your life, man, like… Yeah, no, but…
David Mendenhall: Let's just go talk to Adabra, she'll have an idea of what to do.
Wade: Yeah, next week.
David Mendenhall: next week. Alright, bye-bye.
Kostadis Roussos: Bye-bye.
Wade: G'day, guys.